A Guide to the Purchase Records of Tracy W. McGregor and the Tracy W. McGregor Library, ca. 1929-1970
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Purchase Records of Tracy W. McGregor and the Tracy W. McGregor Library ca. 1929-1970
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
11263-f
675 items (5 Hollinger boxes, ca. 2 linear feet)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These records were transferred from Rare Books to Manuscripts on July 6, 2004.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of the purchase records of Tracy W. McGregor for materials that formed the basis of the Tracy W. McGregor Library of American History at the University of Virginia Library, Special Collections. Many of the invoices are from noted bookseller Henry Stevens Son & Stiles. There are 675 items (5 Hollinger boxes, ca. 2 linear feet), ca. 1929-1970. Also present are two book inventories for books McGregor had stored at the Security Storage Company and at his residence, 1901 Wyoming Avenue, Washington, D.C.; a series of McGregor purchases made by the University of Virginia Library using the McGregor Fund, 1948-1969; a few years of the Tracy W. McGregor Library News Note concerning the McGregor Advisory Committee; and two folders containing proposed additions and revisions to Joseph Sabin's Biblioteca Americana, with annotations by Rare Books staff.
Arrangement
These papers are organized by type of material and chronologically within folders when appropriate.
Contents List
- Accession Book 1933-1936 (Box-folder 1:1)
- Book Inventory--Books Housed at Security Storage Company n.d. (Box-folder 1:2)
- Book Inventory--Books Housed at 1901 Wyoming Avenue n.d. (Box-folder 1:3)
- Invoices A-C 1929-1933 (Box-folder 1:4)
- Invoices D-G 1929-1933 (Box-folder 1:5)
- Invoices H-K 1929-1933 (Box-folder 1:6)
- Invoices L-Q 1929-1933 (Box-folder 2:1)
- Invoices R-Z 1929-1933 (Box-folder 2:2)
- Invoices A-K 1934 (Box-folder 2:3)
- Invoices L-R 1934 (Box-folder 2:4)
- Invoices S-Z 1934 (Box-folder 2:5)
- Invoices A-E 1935 (Box-folder 2:6)
- Invoices F-H 1935 (Box-folder 2:7)
- Invoices I-R 1935 (Box-folder 3:1)
- Invoices S-Z 1935 (Box-folder 3:2)
- Invoices A-L 1936 (Box-folder 3:3)
- Invoices M-Z 1936 (Box-folder 3:4)
- Invoices from Henry Stevens Son & Stiles 1929-1932 May (Box-folder 3:5)
- Invoices from Henry Stevens Son & Stiles 1932 Jun-1933 (Box-folder 3:6)
- Invoices from Henry Stevens Son & Stiles 1934-1936 (Box-folder 3:7)
- McGregor Purchase List 1948-1955 (Box-folder 4:1)
- McGregor Purchase List 1956-1963 Sep (Box-folder 4:2)
- McGregor Purchase List 1963 Oct-1969 (Box-folder 4:3)
- Notebook containing Bibliographic Descriptions of Purchases by Tracy W. McGregor (hand-written) ca. 1929-1931 (Box-folder 4:4)
- Notebook containing Bibliographic Descriptions of Purchases by Tracy W. McGregor ca. 1930-1935 (Box-folder 4:5)
- Notebook containing Bibliographic Descriptions of Purchases by Tracy W. McGregor (type-written or printed) ca. 1935-1936 (Box-folder 4:6)
- Notebook containing Bibliographic Descriptions of Purchases by Tracy W. McGregor ca. 1935-1936 (Box-folder 5:1)
- Sabin Revision 1701-1710 n.d., 1 of 2 folders (Box-folder 5:2)
- Sabin Revision 1701-1710 n.d., 2 of 2 folders (Box-folder 5:3)
- Tracy W. McGregor Library News Note 1966-1970 (Box-folder 5:4)